VLAD-EMIL FLORE

Software / Full Stack Engineer Nürnberg, Germany flore.vlad@gmail.com

DETAILS

NationalityDate of birthRomanian15.11.1985

PROFILE

I am a Software Engineer holding a **Bachelor** and a **Master** in **Computer Science** and being professionally active in this field since 2008. In my professional work, I focused mainly on **Web Development**, **Backend** as well as **Frontend**. In the last 6 years, I have been also working as a **Technical Consultant**, offering implementation and consulting services to different clients, most of them being in Germany.

I am an **Oracle Certified Professional Java SE 8 Programmer** and I enjoy learning new things and taking on new endeavours. A big part of my spare time I dedicate to expanding my knowledge, which is why I continuously attend various courses and programs offered by online learning platforms like **Coursera**, **Edx**, **JetBrains Academy**, **Udacity** or **Udemy**. When time allows it, I also attend and present at **technical conferences**.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Informatics, West University of Timişoara, Timişoara

2008 - 2010

Master of Science in Informatics with a focus on Artificial Intelligence and Distributed Computing

Grade: 9 of 10

Bachelor of Science in Informatics, West University of Timişoara, Timişoara

2004 - 2008

Bachelor of Science in Informatics / Computer Science

Grade: 9.67 of 10 (ranked 7 of 95 graduates)

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Senior Technical Consultant, virtual 7 GmbH, Nürnberg

2014 - 2020

In this period of time, I worked mostly for German clients, on-site and remote, having the positions mentioned below. Other than that, I held a couple of presentations (see Conferences section) and worked on some internal projects.

Lead Software Developer, IT-Systemhaus der Bundesagentur für Arbeit, Nürnberg

2019 - 2020

Tech Stack: Java, Java EE, JUnit, TDD, Angular, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Git, Jenkins, Docker, Linux, Oracle Database, H2, SQL, Jira, Confluence, Bitbucket, Oracle WebLogic Server, Payara Server, OpenAPI Specification

Full Stack Developer, Bundesamt für Migration und Flüchtlinge -BAMF, Nürnberg

2018 - 2019

Tech Stack: Java, Spring Framework, Spring Boot, JUnit, Angular, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Bootstrap, Git, Upsource, Jenkins, Ansible, Linux, Oracle Database, H2, SQL, Jira, Confluence

Software Developer, IT-Systemhaus der Bundesagentur für Arbeit, Nürnberg

2014 - 2018

Tech Stack: Java, Java EE, Oracle WebCenter Content, Oracle Database, SQL, Oracle WebLogic Server, Linux, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Git, Jenkins, Jira, Confluence

Software Developer, virtual7 Romania S.R.L., Timişoara

2008 - 2014

Tech Stack: Java, Java EE, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Oracle Database, SQL, Oracle WebCenter Content, Oracle WebLogic Server

LINKS

Blog Linkedin GitHub

SKILLS Full Stack Development Java Web Development Angular **Computer Programming** Software Craftsmanship Clean Code Test Driven Development Spring Framework **Spring Boot RESTful WebServices** Git GitHub Leadership and Teamwork **DevOps** Docker Ansible **JavaScript** HTML & CSS Bootstrap OpenAPI Specification SQL AWS Lambda Kotlin

LANGUAGES

Python

English German

Romanian

COURSES

Introduction to Computer Science and Programming Using Python, edX (MITx)

AUGUST 2020 - OCTOBER 2020

Core Spring Training, VMware (Pivotal)

MARCH 2020 - MARCH 2020

Software Design and Architecture Specialization, Coursera (University of Alberta)

NOVEMBER 2019 - JUNE 2020

Python for Everybody Specialization, Coursera (University of Michigan)

NOVEMBER 2019 - DECEMBER 2019

Version Control with Git, Coursera (Atlassian)

JULY 2019 - JULY 2019

CERTIFICATIONS

Oracle Certified Professional, Java SE 8 Programmer, online

JUNE 2020 - JUNE 2020

Certificate

Software Design and Architecture, online

JUNE 2020 - JUNE 2020

Certificate

Python for Everybody, online

JANUARY 2020 - JANUARY 2020

Certificate

Oracle Certified Associate, Java SE 8 Programmer, online

MAY 2019 - MAY 2019

Certificate

REFERENCES

Catalina Hritcu (HR Business Partner) from virtual7 Romania S.R.L.

0040787539359

HOBBIES

Travelling, Reading, Learning, Swimming

CONFERENCES

virtual7 GmbH, Freiburg

2019 - 2019

Online Presentation

virtual7 GmbH, Heidelberg

2018 - 2018

PDF Presentation

DOAG, Nürnberg

2017 - 2017

PDF Manuscript

PDF Presentation

DOAG, Nürnberg

2015 - 2015

PDF Manuscript

PDF Presentation

virtual7 Romania S.R.L.
Piata Consiliul Europei, Nr. 2E
United Business Center 3, Timis
J35/3070/2004
RO 16876814
Timisoara, Romania
Tel: 004 0787 539 359

May 29th, 2020

To Whom It May Concern,

It is with great pleasure that I am writing this recommendation letter for Mr. Vlad Flore. I have known Mr. Vlad Flore on a professional level for two years now. During this time, I found him to be detail oriented and a solid and dependable professional. He would strive to understand the background and objectives regarding his assignments and ensure that they get done on time.

He is very proactive, approaches tasks with the right priority, does not need supervision but seeks help when needed. He communicates well and is very collaborative, he loves to learn and teach.

Mr. Vlad Flore has been working at virtual7 since 2008, when he joined the company as a young talent. Since then he has continued to grow and develop and has never stopped being curious and interested in everything that is new in the IT market, and now he's became a senior technical consultant very appreciated in his area of expertise.

Mr. Flore also held many presentations, internal and external, participated in trainings, internal and external and specialized in various fields, also obtaining several certifications. As external presentations I would like to mention that he held twice a conference, in 2015 and 2017 at DOAG (Deutsche Oracle-Anwendergruppe).

He worked on various projects, with different technologies, mainly with Java and Oracle WebCenter Content (Content Management System from Oracle).



virtual7 Romania S.R.L.
Piata Consiliul Europei, Nr. 2E
United Business Center 3, Timis
J35/3070/2004
RO 16876814
Timisoara, Romania
Tel: 004 0787 539 359

After 2014 Mr. Vlad Flore, started to work as a detachment in Germany which taught him to work in an international and multicultural environment.

In all these 11 years of collaboration in Romania, Mr. Vlad Flore proved to be a great colleague, a perfect professional, a person you could always rely on.

He has visited and worked with colleagues from different backgrounds in different countries and is very approachable. He is a natural problem solver. I highly recommend him and i believe that he will be a big asset to any team he works with. I wish him all the best.

Sincerely,

Catalina Hritcu

HR Business Partner

virtual7 Romania S.R.L.